<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-07-20T00:20:18+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Ray Tsai</title><subtitle>Web Designer / Developer / Life Explorer</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Importance of website performance: Should I understand it?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/importance-of-website-performance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Importance of website performance: Should I understand it?" /><published>2014-11-26T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2014-11-26T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/importance-of-website-performance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/importance-of-website-performance/">&lt;p&gt;Website performance sounds like something technical should be handled by web developers. Would it actually be important for designers or project managers to understand what it means?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/website-performance.png&quot; alt=&quot;Website Performance&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-website-performance&quot;&gt;What is website performance?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is more than just page load time, it is also perceived latency. I think good website performance is about delivering the most useful experience, meeting users’ expectations and providing the essential information in a fast, intuitive fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-is-website-performance-important&quot;&gt;Why is website performance important?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good website performance is very important for user experience and user engagement. A huge percentage of internet users are accessing the web with smaller devices through mobile browser and mobile app which has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stevesouders.com/blog/2014/10/09/do-u-webview/&quot;&gt;slower connection speed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Findings report that almost half of mobile users expect pages to load in 2 seconds or less, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webperformancetoday.com/2014/10/22/2014-mobile-ecommerce-page-speed-web-performance/&quot;&gt;40% will abandon a page&lt;/a&gt; that takes longer than 3 seconds to load. Web performance also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webperformancetoday.com/2014/04/09/web-page-speed-affect-conversions-infographic/&quot;&gt;directly affects conversion rate&lt;/a&gt;. Also, Google has &lt;a href=&quot;https://googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.com.au/2010/04/using-site-speed-in-web-search-ranking.html&quot;&gt;taken website performance into account in search rankings&lt;/a&gt;. Lastly, I personally think it is important that we are building fast, useful websites to improves everyone life instead of wasting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-website-performance-non-developers-problem&quot;&gt;Is website performance non-developers problem?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like web developer’s job.
Traditionally, it seems like if the website or interactions are slow, web developers can fix it, right? Not exactly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If designer had designed a website that requires users to download 20MB of images without permission, developers can not fix that. If the project manager had agreed to the client to implement 10 CSS animations firing at the same time with multiple fonts on a landing page, developers can not fix that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designs have to be remade, decisions have to be remade. More time and costs are involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each decision on a website project could have an impact on the website performance. Everyone on the team should be educated about the fundamentals of website performance. It makes the team understand the real problems early on as major decisions are being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-i-implement-website-performance-better&quot;&gt;How can I implement website performance better?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;performance-by-design&quot;&gt;Performance by Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bradfrost.com/blog/post/performance-as-design/&quot;&gt;Web performance should be an early consideration&lt;/a&gt; and be built into the core structure of the product. Because all secondary decisions will base on the core structure. If performance is not considered early, it is like building upon something is already broken. It will be difficult to scale the project and maintain sustainable results. It is expected to have more time and costs involved in a long run or even a rebuild. Read more on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.perftesting.co.uk/performance-by-design-an-agile-approach/2011/11/18/&quot;&gt;Performance By Design – an Agile Approach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prototype-early&quot;&gt;Prototype early&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prototyping websites into real browsers early is the best way to observe any performance problems at the early stage. It is also a great way to get developers and UX designers involved early to give suggestions on performance issues. There are many places still practicing the post-psd workflow, where the designers fine-tune details after client’s feedback over and over again in Photoshop then hand it to the developers only to find out many design don’t work well on a real browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikiwand.com/en/Basecamp_(company)&quot;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt; (formerly known as 37signals), a well-known software company, explains &lt;a href=&quot;https://signalvnoise.com/posts/1061-why-we-skip-photoshop&quot;&gt;why they skip Photoshop&lt;/a&gt; all together and only use quick paper sketch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;know-html-css-and-javascript&quot;&gt;Know HTML, CSS and JavaScript&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are normally the three major elements that users download off your site. Also, normally the main cause of bad website performance if programmed poorly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am NOT saying you need to become good at coding. But if you regularly work on web projects, understanding at least what they are and what they do will really help you in a long run in your career since they are generally the main component of websites. You will be able to communicate with developers much better and comprehend many aspects of website performance much quicker. &lt;a href=&quot;http://htmldog.com/guides/html/beginner/&quot;&gt;You can start from here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;read-googles-web-fundamentals&quot;&gt;Read Google’s Web Fundamentals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/fundamentals/&quot;&gt;Google published a series of articles&lt;/a&gt; on best practices of building web experiences including web performance. They are excellent and will help you avoid a lot of pitfalls while making long-term plans for your apps or websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-readings&quot;&gt;Further readings:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/chriscoyier/lets-do-a-bunch-of-simple-stuff-to-make-websites-faster&quot;&gt;Let’s Do A Bunch of Simple Stuff to Make Websites Faster&lt;/a&gt; – Chris Coyier&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://csswizardry.com/2013/01/front-end-performance-for-web-designers-and-front-end-developers/&quot;&gt;Front-end performance for web designers and front-end developers&lt;/a&gt; – Harry Roberts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2010/01/page-performance-what-to-know-and-what-you-can-do/&quot;&gt;Website Performance: What To Know and What You Can Do&lt;/a&gt; – Christian Heilmann&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webperformancetoday.com/&quot;&gt;Web Performance Today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><summary type="html">Website performance sounds like something technical should be handled by web developers. Would it actually be important for designers or project managers to understand what it means?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life lessons from my basketball training, coaching</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life-lessons-from-my-basketball-training-coaching/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life lessons from my basketball training, coaching" /><published>2014-11-23T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2014-11-23T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life-lessons-from-my-basketball-training-coaching</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life-lessons-from-my-basketball-training-coaching/">&lt;p&gt;I have joined Melbourne University Basketball Club’s domestic competition program for over two years, also started coaching for their domestic B grade women team run by CYMS since the 2014 winter season. I would like to share the life lessons I have learned so far both as a player and a coach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/basketball-training-mubc.png&quot; alt=&quot;Basketball Training MUBC&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;set-specific-goals&quot;&gt;Set Specific Goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For basketball players who would like to improve their game, they have to come to the gym with a purpose, an aim for what player he or she would like to become, or they are really wasting their time. Setting goals is crucial for the development of a basketball player, even a team. I think the same principle holds true in real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By setting specific goals, a person becomes much clearer about where you would like to go in life, who you would like to become in a year, in a month, even in a week. Without setting specific goals, it is too easy to do whatever that comes to the mind and end up going nowhere near where you would like to go. It is important to set specific goal in order to find constructive answers to questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is my specific goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are my weaknesses and strengths for my goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do I need to get there&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How am I going to reach my goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;belief&quot;&gt;Belief&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mental state is a huge factor for basketball games. You have to believe in your ability on the court to be able to excel as a player. Belief is sometimes the difference between an excellent player and an average player. I can practice thousands of hours at the gym, but if I do not believe in myself on the court, I have already lost the battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best player does not have doubt in what they could accomplish. Derrick Rose became the youngest MVP in the history of NBA as of 2014 at the age of 22. A year ago before winning the award, the 21-year-old D-Rose &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usab.com/youth/news/2011/06/how-basketball-players-gain-confidence.aspx&quot;&gt;had no doubt in what he could become&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s3NVmn51zE0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stay-focus&quot;&gt;Stay Focus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to keep yourself on track toward your goal is to stay focus. There are a lot of distractions and people that could influence you. Keep your eyes on the ball, remain focus on the goal you would like to reach and who you would like to become every single day. Listen to two times USA youth basketball gold metal winner Recee Caldwell talking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usab.com/basketball/media/videos/2014/11/recee-caldwell-maintaining-focus.aspx&quot;&gt;Maintaining focus from USA Basketball&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/242401658&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deliberate-practice&quot;&gt;Deliberate Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focusing on the details is vital to grow as a player. When I went to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nolimitsbasketball.com.au/&quot;&gt;No Limit Basketball&lt;/a&gt; shooting clinic run by Pete Maunder, the first thing he said was “To become a great shooter you need to do two things, first is shooting correctly, second is a lot of practice shooting it correctly“. Whenever a player steps onto the court, either for a game, for a practice, or for a drill, the player should understand the key focus of what he/she is doing. Knowing the key focus for what you are doing will help you learn much more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, when players go through a drill, they should understand the focus of the drill whether it would be the right spacing. correct footwork, or proper stance. Otherwise, players will spend hours practicing incorrect movements that are not even slightly useful in a real game. “It’s not the hours you put in your work that counts, it’s the work you put in the hours” – Sam Ewing. For further reading, I suggest this article by James Clear &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesclear.com/deliberate-practice&quot;&gt;“Lessons on Success and Deliberate Practice from Mozart, Picasso, and Kobe Bryant“&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hard-work&quot;&gt;Hard Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful basketball players talk a lot about hard-work pays off. To become a great player is a long term commitment. It is not something that happens overnight. It requires consistent effort and preparation every single day, so that you are ready when the opportunity comes. In my basketball experience, I also believe there is no shortcut to success and growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best NBA players still work their tails off every day no matter how successful they already are. Listen to these people talk about hard work: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ray_Allen&quot;&gt;Ray Allen&lt;/a&gt; – 10 times NBA all-star, NBA’s all-time leader in three-point field goals made as of 2014. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Paul&quot;&gt;Chris Paul&lt;/a&gt; – 7 times NBA all-star, 6 times NBA steals leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/242401370&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/242401707&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feeling-vs-principle&quot;&gt;Feeling vs. Principle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days, I do not even feel like waking up or going to the gym to practice. If I listen to my little feelings, at the end of my day I would have done nothing. If I listen to my feeling, I would just quit whenever I feel pain or whenever I get tired. What are your principles? What would you like to accomplish today or this week? Sticking to your principles is what get you one step closer to your goal each day, not your feelings. “At the end of your feeling is nothing, but at the end of every principle is a promise” – Eric Thomas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/242401504&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I do not own any of the audio, video materials on this article.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">I have joined Melbourne University Basketball Club’s domestic competition program for over two years, also started coaching for their domestic B grade women team run by CYMS since the 2014 winter season. I would like to share the life lessons I have learned so far both as a player and a coach.</summary></entry></feed>
